SEAN MORAN MSIS MCP



FULL STACK APPLICATION DEVELOPER

7343 Conch Blvd Seminole, FL 33777
<u>seanpmoran@outlook.com</u> (preferred)
253-224-6702 (Mobile)
http://www.linkedin.com/in/moranseanp

I am a well-rounded and multi-certified ASP.NET MVC, Azure, SharePoint, and SQL Server professional, with successful projects using a wide variety of technologies, but favoring the Microsoft development stack. I enjoy staying on the cutting edge of development (.NET Core, Blazor, Angular etc.) and using the Azure laaS and PaaS platforms to create efficiencies that enable organizations to get more done, at less cost, and with less maintenance. I believe in building nimble distributed applications using the proper tools, over building monolithic and difficult to maintain centralized applications.

I have over 25 years of solid analysis and development experience with a wide variety of leading organizations. These include, but are not limited to Microsoft, Tech Data, The Boeing

IMPORTANT DETAILS AT A GLANCE

- Over 30 Years of Project Delivery Experience
- Over 25 Years of Development Experience
- Over 4 years of full-time technical training and classroom management experience
- Over 19 Years of Microsoft .Net Experience
- Scored in the 93rd percentile of the Robert Half C# examination.
- 10+ Years of SharePoint Design and Development Experience
- 1+ Year of Microsoft Dynamics CRM Development Experience
- Speaker and Contributor to the Larger SharePoint Community
- Published Multiple Times in Popular Trade Periodicals

Company, Nordstrom, The United States Army, The United States Air Force, The State of Washington, Alaska Airlines, Wachovia Securities, Russell Investments and Weyerhaeuser. I have completed short-to-long term IT projects in the Financial Services, Insurance, Manufacturing, Aerospace, Airline, Entertainment, Marketing, Retail and Software industries, as well as in Federal and State Government and the US Military. I possess a broad overview and understanding of business needs and processes that must be considered in any IT-related project.

Please note that this resume is limited to about ten or so years of history. Thus, detailed information about my work at Microsoft, The Boeing Company, Hewlett Packard, Weyerhaeuser, United States Department of Energy and others has been omitted.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION SYSTEMS (2015) – MINOT STATE UNIVERSITY

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS INFORMATION SYSTEMS (2005) – BELLEVUE UNIVERSITY

ASSOCIATE IN TECHNOLOGY - GENERAL – PIERCE COLLEGE

CERTIFICATE IN PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES – PIERCE COLLEGE

RELEVANT INDUSTRY CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Certified Professional			
Number: E549-2419	Issued by: Microsoft	Date Issued: 10/2009	
Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals			
Number: H036-4124	Issued by: Microsoft	Date Issued: 2/2019	
MTA: Database Administration Fundamentals			
Number: E549-2420	Issued by: Microsoft	Date Issued: 12/2013	
MTA: Web Development Fundamentals using C#			
Number: E888-5938	Issued by: Microsoft	Date Issued: 07/2014	
MTA: Software Development Fundamentals using C#			
Number: E888-5939	Issued by: Microsoft	Date Issued: 07/2014	
MCTS: Microsoft Windows SharePoint Services 3.0: Application Development using C#			
Number: C051-0435	Issued by: Microsoft	Date Issued: 9/2009	
MCTS: Microsoft Windows SharePoint Services 3.0: Configuration			
Number: C051-0436	Issued by: Microsoft	Date Issued: 10/2009	
CompTIA Certified Technical Trainer (CTT+) - Classroom			
Number: JTIV2214	Issued by: CompTIA	Date Issued: 01/2014	
CompTIA Security+			
Number: 262477731	Issued by: CompTIA	Date Issued: 2/2010	
Umbraco Microsoft.NET Level 1 Developer			
Number: N/A	Issued by: Umbraco	Date Issued: 4/2016	
Umbraco Microsoft.NET Level 2 Developer			
Number: N/A	Issued by: Umbraco	Date Issued: 4/2016	
Certificate in Programming Languages			
Number: N/A	Issued by: Pierce College	Date Issued: 9/2004	

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

MICROSOFT AZURE - ASP.NET MVC/ASP.NET CORE - AZURE SQL DEVELOPER

Data Age Business Systems January 2017 to Present

I was hired to help complete a troubled and incomplete outsourced project. I created or transformed projects supported by the following technologies:

- Designed and built asynchronous microservices using Azure Durable Functions, Logic Apps and REST APIs to enable customer payments to a 3rd party service, and automatic update of the payments in the POS application.
- Designed and built a fully responsive and asynchronous public facing portal web application using .Net Core 2x Razor Pages. This portal included a substantial asynchronous REST API implemented through Entity Framework Core, also done in .Net Core 2x. Authorization for data management uses JWT authentication protected by SHA512 encryption and salted password storage. The project implemented the Repository and the MVVM Design Patterns, Bootstrap 4 with Font Awesome, HTML5, customized CSS, Alertify.js for notifications.
- Designed and built an asynchronous Azure Blob Storage service solution using .Net Core 2x, replacing storage of images in databases with Azure Blob storage.
- Redesigned and rebuilt a very large ASP.NET MVC web app project, migrating it from costly AWS virtual machines to a consumption based Azure Web Applications.
- Simplified and completed a large Web API project, also migrating it from costly AWS virtual machines to a consumption based Azure Web Service. Used the .NET Entity Framework v6.x.
- Designed and implemented a strategy for Azure SQL database servers and elastic pools in each environment.
- Completely reconfigured several SQL Server databases to accommodate Azure SQL and migrated them to the new Azure SQL environment.
- Performed performance tuning on many SQL Server databases, implementing a comprehensive indexing strategy, as well as rewriting many bloated stored procedures.
 Several stored procedures saw increased performance from ~7 minutes to 2 seconds or so.
- Created several new Azure microservices to replace existing Windows services on AWS. Took advantage of Visual Studio 2017 tooling and Azure queue storage.
- Reconfigured a large Windows point of sale application to be smart client served by the Azure framework.
- Replaced an expensive SQL Server Reporting Services virtual machine on AWS with a
 modern Azure-based reporting system. Special emphasis was placed on finding a serverless
 solution that could support the migration of many reports with the least amount of cost and
 effort.

- Assisted in the creation of a continuous integration deployment system using VSTS and Azure.
- Designed and created new Azure subscription environments for development, test and production.
- Repaired several Telerik Web and WinForms application deficiencies (paging, proper queries etc.

MICROSOFT WEB - AZURE DEVELOPER (CONTRACT)

Skybridge Resources at Tech Data – Clearwater FL August 2017 to December 2017

I was hired to assist in a SharePoint migration from SharePoint versions 2010 and 2013 to SharePoint Online. I also handled many repairs and customizations to a heavily branded SharePoint Online Intranet portal. I completed projects supported by the following technologies:

- Developed a new SharePoint Online Publishing Site approval and provisioning tool using Microsoft Patterns and Practices guidance, Microsoft Azure functions and queue storage, SharePoint list webhooks subscribed to Azure functions, and Nintex O365 workflow.
- Developed and deployed new responsive SharePoint webparts using the new SharePoint Framework (SPFx), including the new build and deployment tools of NPM, Gulp, Yeoman etc.
- Developed a new asynchronous SharePoint Online image compression tool using Microsoft Azure functions (C#/JavaScript), and queue and blob storage, and SharePoint list webhooks subscribed to Azure functions. This enabled images for news articles to be easily compressed 50-90% without an appreciable loss of quality.
- Added and/or refactored a substantial amount of CSS in a heavily customized Intranet site, enabling the doubling of site performance.
- Built and published new page layouts to facilitate migrations.
- Manually repaired and reconfigured many imported/transferred sites with migration issues from SharePoint 2010 to SharePoint Online.

MICROSOFT ASP.NET MVC - SQL SERVER DEVELOPER USING C#

MORAN CONSULTING LLC
JUNE 2017 TO PRESENT

I created projects supported by the following technologies:

• Developed a new asynchronous student REST API using Microsoft ASP.NET Web API (v4.6x). This provides content about online JavaScript-based games, including binary images, and is accessible for read by anyone with authorization. Authorization for data management uses JWT authentication, protected by SHA512 encryption and salted password storage. The

service stores data in a Microsoft Azure SQL Server database, and is hosted as an Azure Web App.

- Developed a new ASP.NET MVC data maintenance application that manages the data in the above described REST service. This application uses both the built-in scaffolding features of MVC, as well as the AJAX functionality provided by the framework.
- Developed a small new game using the client-side Angular framework. This game uses the above referenced REST service for data access.

TECHNICAL TRAINER – MICROSOFT PROGRAMMING AND DATABASE TECHNOLOGIES

PIERCE COLLEGE - PUYALLUP, WA SEPTEMBER 2013 TO JUNE 2017

I spent 4 years developing and delivering high quality training to professional/technical college students. I have completed this contract and have returned to my development career. The details below demonstrate my holistic understanding of the field of Information Technology, the technologies that I am experienced with, and my ability to understand and work in a team environment that values the abilities of all members of the team. I have created and taught the following courses, of which the following technologies were prominent:

HTML5, ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, SQL Server with advanced SQL and Database Administration, CSS, Bootstrap, C#, ADO.NET, JavaScript and jQuery. This is not an exhaustive list, so please ask if you want more information.

CIS121 - Introduction to Computer Information Systems	CIS210 - Business Analysis	
CIS280 - Systems Analysis and Design	CIS275 - Business Intelligence	
CS&141 – Computer Science I - Python	CS202 – Computer Science II - Java	
CIS122 - Structured Program Design using C#	CIS123 - Introduction to Object Oriented	
	Programming using C#	
CIS185 – Intermediate Object-Oriented	CIS215 - Client-Side Programming using	
Programming using C# and SQL Server	HTML5, CSS and JavaScript	
CIS216 - Server-Side Programming using	CIS260 – Database Fundamentals (using SQL	
ASP.NET MVC	Server)	
CIS261 - Beginning Structured Query	CIS269 - Advanced Structured Query	
Language (T-SQL)	Language (T-SQL)	
CIS262 - Database Administration		

MICROSOFT SOLUTION ARCHITECT – NOTE: ALL NORDSTROM POSITIONS ARE FOR THE SAME TEAM NORDSTROM - SEATTLE, WA SEPTEMBER 2012 TO SEPTEMBER 2013

- Responsible for solution architecture and agile development efforts of the Process and Collaborations group at Nordstrom. All SharePoint work was done in C#/JavaScript, Twitter Bootstrap, jQuery, REST and other supporting technologies.
- Responsible for the design and led the development efforts of the new SharePoint 2013 Intranet project. Performed all UI development using SharePoint Design Manager, JavaScript, CSS, Adobe Dreamweaver, Photoshop and Fireworks. Developed social feature web-parts using the client-side JavaScript object model. Worked closely with the analysts and developers during spring planning to design and implement the most useful feature set for each sprint.
- Designed and developed a 2013 Client-Side Object Model Search and Taxonomy-based Windows Service application to auto-tag documents based on a corporate glossary.
- Designed and built a division portal that was specially designed to be lightweight and portable. The portal was fully list driven, with both native lists and BCS-surfaced external content types. The solution relied upon sandboxed web-parts, jQuery, jQuery UI, SPServices and custom CSS. The result was a robust portal with the ability to deploy any time day or night.
- Mentored analysts and developers.

PROJECT MANAGER

NORDSTROM - SEATTLE, WA JANUARY 2012 TO AUGUST 2012

- Development Lead and Scrum Master at Nordstrom.
- Responsible for supporting the Process and Collaboration team at Nordstrom. This involved managing people, operations and projects.
- Using a combination of agile development methodologies, I led the migration from an organically grown SharePoint 2007 implementation to a rather good and useful 2010 implementation. Attention was paid to taxonomy/findability, social integration, custom application migration and custom look and feel.
- Additionally, I was responsible for the complete management of full time, contract, nearshore and offshore teams. This included HR function as well as resource allocation among projects.
- While I was successful in this role, I did not enjoy it as much as I enjoy architecting and creating useful solutions. Thus, I stepped into an architecture role at Nordstrom.

MICROSOFT WEB DEVELOPER - SENIOR

NORDSTROM - SEATTLE, WA SEPTEMBER 2011 TO JANUARY 2012

- Development Lead and Scrum Master for Nordstrom PCS group. All SharePoint work was done in C#/JavaScript, Twitter Bootstrap, jQuery, REST and other supporting technologies.
- Responsible for application architecture and agile development efforts of the Process and Collaborations group at Nordstrom.
- Supported design, development and development for a wide range of applications, including a social (Yammer-like) presence, the company's first SharePoint-iPad selling tool on the floor of the full line stores, and the MOSS-based digital asset management system for the photo studio.
- Mentored other developers.

SHAREPOINT CONSULTANT - INDEPENDENT

MORAN CONSULTING LLC
DECEMBER 2010 TO SEPTEMBER 2011

- Worked with Fortune 100 clients in the Southeastern United States on SharePoint 2010 development and implementation projects. All SharePoint work was done in C#/JavaScript, Twitter Bootstrap, jQuery, REST and other supporting technologies.
- Developed and implemented complex custom workflows allowing farms around the world to interact.
- Developed a custom web-part based image editing and management system using NeoDynamics imaging components and Telerik ASP.Net AJAX controls.
- Developed custom Visual Web Parts in SharePoint Server 2010.
- Developed custom lists utilizing custom event receivers, fields, site columns and content types.
- Developed custom branding using custom minimal master pages and CSS.
- Integrated complete Telerik ASP.Net AJAX components package into SharePoint Server 2010 as a custom feature.
- Developed custom code-based state machine workflows using ASPX forms and custom content types to facilitate process improvement.
- Deployed solutions using PowerShell for SharePoint 2010.

MICROSOFT SHAREPOINT DEVELOPER AT UNITED STATES AIR FORCE

L-3 COMMUNICATIONS - SUMTER, SC JANUARY 2010 TO DECEMBER 2010

- This position and the position with InfoReliance were essentially the same job. The initial project with InfoReliance completed successfully, and I move to L3 to help support the installation.
- Microsoft SharePoint Server developer on a 34 farm deployment. All SharePoint work was done in C#/JavaScript/Silverlight and other supporting technologies.
- Developed site provisioning tool using Silverlight inside SharePoint Server 2007. Complex sites and permissions were automatically provisioned from Excel spreadsheet data across site collections on 34 farms throughout the world.
- Developed custom Web Parts, using both code only, as well as user control methods.
- Developed custom lists utilizing custom event receivers, fields, site columns and content types.
- Developed custom application pages.
- Developed custom branding solutions using custom minimal master pages and CSS.
- Integrated complete Developer Express components package into Microsoft Office SharePoint Server as a custom feature.
- Integrated complete Microsoft ASP.Net AJAX framework into Microsoft Office SharePoint Server as a custom feature.
- Developed custom code-based state machine workflows using ASPX forms and custom content types to facilitate process improvement.
- Implemented standardized process for creating solution packages with WSP Builder that facilitated automated builds.
- As this project was spread out over several countries in the Middle East, all development was code based. This allowed for the extensive development of custom feature receivers.
- Mentored other developers.

MICROSOFT SHAREPOINT DEVELOPER AT UNITED STATES AIR FORCE

InfoReliance Corporation – Sumter, SC October 2008 to January 2010

See the L-3 position above for information about this position.

MICROSOFT .NET DEVELOPER

ADVANCED AUTOMATION CONSULTING - COLUMBIA, SC SEPTEMBER 2007 TO SEPTEMBER 2008

- Performed new and maintenance development for the Microsoft CRM 3.0 implementation.
- Performed new and maintenance development SharePoint Microsoft Office SharePoint Server.
- Served as SharePoint administrator.
- Integrated Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services to Microsoft Office SharePoint Server.
- Completed custom security to provide granular rights to users of differing access levels at varying geographical locations.
- Developed custom SharePoint web parts against SQL Server databases and web services.
- Developed SharePoint BDC application and associated ASP.Net web services.
- Developed document approval workflows between bank associations using K2 BlackPearl.
- Developed management application to allow new loan requests to integrate with CRM via new web services.
- Developed AJAX web application to control SQL Server Reporting Services report delivery.
- Integrated reports with SharePoint document libraries via new custom SharePoint web services.
- Developed data-driven Google mapping application that features extensive server-side generated JavaScript to take advantage of the Microsoft AJAX extensions.
- Developed MDI-based Windows Smart Client management application against new corporate data warehouse.

MICROSOFT ASP.NET/SQL SERVER DEVELOPER AT UNITED STATES ARMY

DYNAMICS RESEARCH INC. - FORT LEE, VA FEBRUARY 2007 TO SEPTEMBER 2007

- Performed new and maintenance development for the U.S. Army's Food Management Information System (AFMIS), as well as supporting tools.
- AFMIS is an ASP.Net web application that is back up to SQL Server databases.
- Developed Smart Client software using VB.Net and SQL Server to manage database manipulation and ETL processes.
- Developed SQL Server Integration Services projects to manage database manipulation.
- Developed processes and documentation for upgrade to SQL Server 2005 from SQL Server 2000.
- Upgraded portions of the AFMIS project to take advantage of AJAX technologies.

MICROSOFT ASP.NET/SQL SERVER DEVELOPER AT UNITED STATES ARMY

NEWTEC LLC - FORT LEWIS, WA SEPTEMBER 2006 TO FEBRUARY 2007

- Development lead on a Future Combat Simulation project team.
- Responsible, along with other team members, for the design and delivery of a GIS-enabled,
 C# and SQL Server 2005 based data collection and reporting system.
- Responsible for the re-engineering and implementation of the ASP.Net 2.0 web-portal that is a part of the DCARS project.

VARIOUS OLDER PROJECTS

Various

OCTOBER 1985 TO SEPTEMBER 2006

Participated in several projects with Microsoft, The Boeing Company, Hewlett Packard, Weyerhaeuser, United States Department of Energy and others.

Further details of my career are available upon request.